Contact

bettyjcawthon@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/betty-ware-9a434877 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Grant Writing
Federal Grants Management
Grant Administration

Betty Ware

Senior Accountant at Memphis Light, Gas and Water (MLGW) Memphis, Tennessee

Summary

Experienced Senior Accountant with a demonstrated history of working in the utilities industry. Skilled in Tax Preparation, Microsoft Word, Oracle Reports, Plant Operations, and Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (GAAP). Strong accounting professional with a Bachelor's of Business Administration focused in Accounting and Finance from The University of Memphis.

Experience

Memphis Light, Gas and Water (MLGW) 14 years 8 months

Senior Accountant October 2007 - Present

Responsible for the medium to complex accounting activities associated with maintaining general ledger accounts and for developing financial statements and reports. Reconciliation of account balances for annual audits. Analysis of financial transactions to determine accuracy and completeness of entries. Analysis of variances between fiscal years and budget to actual in order to provide explanation of variances (reports.) Grant writing and reporting functions. Perform various studies to determine rates. Researching policies to ensure GASB, FERC and governmental law compliance. May provide functional advice or training to less experienced accountants.

Accounting Representative
July 2004 - October 2007 (3 years 4 months)

Processed work requests via Capital Budget for various projects. Created/posted journal vouchers to correct Plant account records. Reconciled monthly balance sheets to Plant records. Moved assets from W.I.P. to Plant books (in service.) Calculated depreciation on Plant accounts for salvaged assets. Prepared monthly and quarterly billing statements for the City of Memphis and the surrounding municipalities for Street Light Additions and Retirements.

Education

The University of Memphis

Bachelor's of Business Administration, Accounting and Finance · (1995 - 2000)